# MATEUS TORQUATO DE MEDEIROS

# • DETAILS •

+55 (48) 99861-3852 matteus.torquato@gmail.com

#### o SKILLS o

**Javascript** 

CSS3

HTML5

MongoDB

React

Git

SQL

Angular

Laravel

Typescript

PHP

Ionic

Serverless

Node.js

AWS

Bootstrap

MySQL

jQuery

Docker

# LANGUAGES

Portuguese

English

# PROFILE

Bachelor in Information and Communications Technology, with almost a decade of experience in systems analysis and development. In my opinion, software is changeable and living things, requiring constant dedication and focus to grow healthily. I believe in different ways of thinking, producing, living and solving problems.

I've been working as a Full Stack Web Developer for about 5 years, having experience with PHP + Laravel/Lumen, Angular, React, Node, and AWS environment using AWS Lambdas + Serverless framework. I'm not stuck to technologies and I'm passionate about learning and technology in general, looking to study something new every day. Nevertheless, I've been studying and working a lot with JavaScript currently, and this has been the main focus of my studies in recent years.

#### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

## Full Stack Engineer at Bravi

February 2020 — Present

At Bravi, I was assigned to a financial sector project in the Quanta Previdência team, focused on the development of the Plataforma project, which aims to be a self-service platform for pension plan participants, in addition to creating an easy way for new people to join the available plans, eliminating the use of paper and making everything more transparent.

We used Scrum and its ceremonies, with the planning, scoring the tasks in the planning poker, at the end of each sprint we have the sprint retrospective as well, in addition to daily meetings throughout the course of the sprint.

In the frontend, we basically use Angular in the development of the platform in the logged area, WordPress in the landing page, and to guarantee the quality, Jasmine + Karma help us in our unit tests.

In our backend, we adopted the BFF (Backends For Frontends) architecture, and to ensure greater security and scalability we used the AWS framework to assist us in this. The backend is built in NodeJS and uses the Serverless framework to make easier our integration with AWS and manage our Lambda Functions. To ensure that everything is in compliance, we use Jest to do our unit tests on the backend.

We use several resources made available by AWS to assist us in our development, including:

- Lambda Functions, to reduce costs, not requiring a 24/7 machine available to access resources that are not used all the time.
- S3 for general file storage.
- DynamoDB as a non-relational database.
- EC2 for a few services.

And last, but not least, to take care of all this, we use Jenkins, responsible for managing all the application's pipelines and deployment, orchestrating what will happen with each branch we send (we use Gitflow on our pipeline), be it a hotfix for production, or a bugfix for a release.

The second project I worked on at Bravi was a project from EposNow, the first international project I participated in, from a company located in the UK. At first, I was allocated to deal more with some frontend stuff, but I also have to be in constant contact

with the backend and the APIs. On this position I mainly worked with React.js to create an application responsible for bulk import massive data using .csv or .xlsl files.

#### Full Stack Developer at Exon

August 2018 — February 2020

It was at Exon where I started to really venture into web development using PHP with Laravel and SQLServer database, where I participated in the development and maintenance of the modular manufacturing management system, which aims to meet the needs of the entire flow of the production process of a company, from the entry of raw materials, storage, production logistics, and product loading.

This is where I started to improve my front-end skills, working with CSS3 (with Bootstrap), JavaScript (with JQuery) for interface development. I ended up learning a little bit about Jaspersoft/Ireport too, as I was also responsible for creating new reports.

Over time, I was allocated to take care of a few mobile projects (Android and iOS) developed in Ionic + Angular. At the end of my experience at Exon, I ended up building a project using Ionic from scratch for sizing photovoltaic energy systems and calculating investment returns.

#### Software developer at Ema

December 2013 — August 2018

I started my work at Ema as a member of the ERP (Enterprise Resource Planning) team, giving maintenance and developing new features using Delphi XE. Here I had the opportunity to work with several relational databases, such as Firebird, Oracle and PostgreSQL, with multi-tier architecture.

After a while, I was allocated as an analyst responsible for the changes in the POS (Point of Sale) system, and responsible for the changes necessary for the system to comply with the rules of the PAF-ECF (mandatory rules in most of Brazil), as well such as the approval of the software with the competent authorities. This software is also written in Delphi language. I participated in this project for a long time at Ema, being the main responsible for developing new features and fixes, but also acting as Product Owner, making decisions about what would be done, how, and when.

It was here that I began to really understand how a software company works, all its processes, how to deal with customers, as well as teamwork and planning. It was a time of great learning, and I grew a lot professionally, especially in relation to my soft skills, where I discovered points where I could improve myself that went beyond technology, such as communication, flexibility, proactivity, and resilience.

## EDUCATION

## Bachelor, Universidade Federal de Santa Catarina

January 2016 — December 2019

Bachelor in Information and Communication Technology. My completion of course work was developing a native android app called PetID.

The objective of this work was to develop an Android application combining NFC technology for animal identification in order to find a solution to the high incidence of abandonment in the country. Application development was done through the Android Studio platform using the PostgreSQL database, which was hosted in the cloud for free through the Heroku platform. It is developed with a focus on NGOs, clinics, and owners who have access to an NFC smartphone, allowing them to verify essential information about the animal.